# JACOB **DAWSON**

301 S 5<sup>th</sup> St, Ames, IA 50010 · (515) 402-8669 dawson@iastate.edu · linkedin.com/in/jdawson98 · github.com/JacobDawson98

Dependable undergraduate software engineering student with academic and professional experience in algorithm development, object-oriented programming, test driven development, and web development.

Possesses additional experience in teamwork, critical thinking, and leadership.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **MAY 2018 - PRESENT**

## **PROGRAMMING INTERN, IMT COMPUTER SERVICES**

- Utilize test driven development to produce highly modularized, flexible, and extensible, code.
- Redesigned the frontend of the company dashboard to improve customer experience, update APIs, and to make way towards a consistent user interface among products.

#### **AUG 2018 - PRESENT**

## **TEACHING ASSISTANT, IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY**

- Assist students with introductory web development assignments.
- Accurately grade assignments and provide detailed feedback.

#### **JANUARY 2018 - MAY 2018**

## **CS STUDENT SYSTEMS SUPPORT,** IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY

- Created and responded to support cases, submitted by faculty and staff, whom experienced hardware or software issues.
- Provided proactive communication which increased customer satisfaction and understanding.

# **EDUCATION**

AUG 2016 - MAY 2020

## **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY**

Classification: JuniorCumulative GPA: 2.97

## **RELEVANT SKILLS**

- Development: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Ability to work in a collaborative environment, utilizing agile practices.

- Frameworks: Ember.js, Django, and Node
- Environments: UNIX and Windows